A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Elderly Program, SG 2, Series 11 FA1457
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Elderly Program, SG 2, Series 11
1993-2002
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA1457
12.47 Cubic Feet 28 letter-size document boxes and one half-letter document box, 1 oversize box and 1 record storage box
10.45 Cubic Feet 27 letter-size document boxes and one half-letter document box.
Arrangement
Records remain in original order, as received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund records were donated to RAC in 1985. The initial transfer of archival records to RAC began in 1986, and tranfers continue on a regular basis. These Elderly Program filers were transferred to RAC in multiple accessions in 1998-2002.
Scope and Contents
This series documents the Commonwealth Fund's activities in the area of elderly care including but not necessarily limited to medicare, medicaid, nursing home care, treatment, as well as chronic illness and end of life care. The records consist of staff program files, advisory committee meeting records, program reviews, and pertinent grants. The grant files often contain records pertaining to: budget and administration, proposals and development, articles and background information, correspondence, grant products and related program files.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Sound recordings
- Advancing the Well-Being of Elderly People - Advisory Committee, 1996 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Advancing the Well-Being of Elderly People - Advisory Committee - Briefing Book Materials, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Urban Institute (94-119) - Fostering the Independence of Frail Elders - Advisory Committee Meeting, 1994 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Urban Institute (94-119) - Fostering the Independence of Frail Elders - Advisory Committee Meeting, 1994 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Urban Institute (94-119) - Fostering the Independence of Frail Elders - Management Meeting, 1994 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Urban Institute (94-119) - Fostering the Independence of Frail Elders - Advisory Committee Meeting, 1994 December (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Urban Institute (94-119) - Fostering the Independence of Frail Elders - Administration of Program, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Urban Institute (94-119) - Fostering the Independence of Frail Elders - Auxiliary File (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Conferences, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Urban Institute - NY Home Care Evaluation (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Future of Medicare (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Picker Patient-Centered Care Program Review - Notes, 1996 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Board Proposal Review Memos, 1996 April (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Board Proposal Review Memos, 1996 July (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Managed Care and Low Income Populations, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Yale University (95-47) - Preventing Acute Confusion in Hospitalized Elderly Patients - Proposals and Budget, 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Yale University (95-47) - Preventing Acute Confusion in Hospitalized Elderly Patients - Grant Products, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Yale University (95-47) - Preventing Acute Confusion in Hospitalized Elderly Patients - Correspondence and Background, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Yale University (94-90) - Preventing Acute Confusion in Hospitalized Elderly Patients - Proposal and Budget, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Yale University (94-90) - Preventing Acute Confusion in Hospitalized Elderly Patients - Grant Products, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Yale University (94-90) - Preventing Acute Confusion in Hospitalized Elderly Patients - Correspondence and Background, 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Lewin-VHI, Inc. - Claxton (96610), 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Stanford - Garber (96170) - Grant Products, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Stanford - Garber (96170) - Administration and Proposal, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Stanford - Garber (96170) - Background (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Stanford - Garber (96170) - Write Ups (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Stanford - Garber (96170), 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- National Civic League (95-53), 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Urban Institute - Moon (96178) - Medicare's Future - Program Notes, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Urban Institute - Moon (96178) - Medicare's Future - Write Ups, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Urban Institute - Moon (96178) - Medicare's Future - Administration, Proposal and Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Urban Institute - Moon (96178) - Medicare's Future - Grant Products, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- National Academy for State Health Policy (NASHP) - Riley (96640) - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- National Academy for State Health Policy (NASHP) - Riley (96640) - Administration, Proposal and Background, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- National Academy for State Health Policy (NASHP) - Riley (96640) - Write Ups (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Health Resources, Inc. (95-48), 1994-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Health Resources, Inc. (95-48) - Proposal Development, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Families USA Foundation (871068) - Medicare Managed Care, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Alliance for Health Reform (980077, 970267) - Medicare, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Institute of Medicine (IOM) - Medicare Managed Care, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Mount Sinai Medical Center - Cassel-Siu (96965) - Quality Indicators for Care at End of Life, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Evaluated Medicaid Managed Long Term Capitation Project (95-18) (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- First Annual Meeting of the Paul B. Beeson Physician Faculty Scholars in Aging Research Program, Arlington, VA, 1996 May 13-15 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - Resident Care Library - Training Manual and Handouts, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - Resident Care Library - Module 1: The New Resident, 1995; 13 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11724)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research. Digital access copy available.
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - Resident Care Library - Module 2: Up and About: Minimizing the Risk of Fall Injuries, 1995; 15 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11725)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - Resident Care Library - Module 3: Working With Residents Who Wander, 1995; 13 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11726)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - Resident Care Library - Module 4: Getting Hit, Grabbed and Threatened: What It Means, What To Do, 1995; 15 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11727)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - Resident Care Library - Module 5: Staying Restraint Free Evenings, Nights and Weekends, 1995; 13 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11728)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - Resident Care Library - Module 6: Now That The Restraints Are Off, What Do We Do, 1995; 14 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11729)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - The Management Perspective Video and Guide - A Family Guide to Restraint-Free Care - Viewing and Resource Guide, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - The Management Perspective, 1995; 17 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11730)
- Everyone Wins: Quality Care Without Restraints - A Family Guide to Restraint-Free Care, 1995; 12 minutes; VHS (Box 1A, Tape AV 11731)
- Nursing Home Restraints Program Review - Briefing Materials, 1996 August 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Improving Health Care Systems for Older People Presentation, University of California, San Francisco, 1998 March 25 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Louis Harris and Associates, Inc. - Problems Facing Elderly Americans Living Alone (Study No. 854010), 1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Louis Harris and Associates, Inc. - The Importance of Choice in Medicaid Home Care Programs: Maryland, Michigan, and Texas (Study No. 902064), 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- The Urban Institute - Weiner-Holahan (96951), 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- The Urban Institute - Weiner-Holahan (96951) - Proposal and Administration, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Howard (980187) - Health Policy Briefings - Proposal Development, 1996-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Howard (980187) - Health Policy Briefings - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Howard (980187) - Health Policy Briefings - Administration and Budget (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Howard (980187) - Health Policy Briefings - Grant Products (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Medicare - "Defined Contributions" - Remedy or Poison Pill: Options and Implications of Changing How Medicare Finances Beneficiary's Care, 1998 July 24; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 84 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9969)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  The first 30 seconds are difficult to hear.
- Alliance for Health Reform - Medicare and Drugs: Finding the Right Prescription - A Briefing on Ways to Improve Access to Pharmaceuticals for Medicare Beneficiaries, 1999 January 25; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 88 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9970)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Health Care Inflation: Is the Sleeping Dragon Awakening - A Briefing on the Most Recent Data, What it Means and What to Expect, 1998 March 2; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 94 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9971)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (95-29), 1995-1999 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- The Urban Institute - Weiner (980779) - Monitoring and Assessing State Long-Term Care Policy, Phase Two - Administration and Budget, 1998-2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- The Urban Institute - Weiner (980779) - Monitoring and Assessing State Long-Term Care Policy, Phase Two - Proposal Development and Background, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- The Urban Institute - Weiner (980779) - Monitoring and Assessing State Long-Term Care Policy, Phase Two - Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- The Urban Institute - Weiner (980779) - Monitoring and Assessing State Long-Term Care Policy, Phase Two - Grant Products, 1998-2001 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
- The Urban Institute - Weiner (980779) - Monitoring and Assessing State Long-Term Care Policy, Phase Two - Grant Products, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (20000698) - Annual Meeting and Promotional Activities, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (20000698) - Sixth Annual Meeting, Hutchinson Island, FL, 2001 June 16-19 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (20000698) - Sixth Annual Meeting, Hutchinson Island, FL - Final Report, 2001 June 16-19 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Research Triangle Institute - Hawes (970435), 1999-2001 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Health Research Inc. (95-18) - Evaluated Medicaid Long Term Care Capitation Program, 1994-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Health Research Inc. (95-18) - Evaluated Medicaid Long Term Care Capitation Program - RFP, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Health Research Inc. (95-18) - Evaluated Medicaid Long Term Care Capitation Program - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Health Research Inc. (95-18) - Evaluated Medicaid Long Term Care Capitation Program - Grant Products, 1994-2001 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Myers Research Institute - Hawes (PDF 990528) (Box 14, Folder 1)
- American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging (AAHSA) - Stone - Promoting Quality in Nursing Homes: The Wellspring Model (20000377 PDF), 1999-2001 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging (AAHSA) - Stone - Promoting Quality in Nursing Homes: The Wellspring Model (20000377 PDF) - Background, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Georgetown University - Fox (980512), 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (970942) - Proposal and Administration (Box 14, Folder 5)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (970942) - Background and Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (970942) - Grant Products, 1994-1999 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (990740) - Administration, 1999-2001 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (990740) - Progress Reports, 1999-2002 (Box 15, Folder 2-4)
- Harvard Medical School (95521) - Survey of the Quality of Life for Patients with Life-Threatening Illnesses, 1995-1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Harvard Medical School (95521) - Survey of the Quality of Life for Patients with Life-Threatening Illnesses - Selection of Survey Firm, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Harvard Medical School (95521) - Survey of the Quality of Life for Patients with Life-Threatening Illnesses - Grant Products, 1994-1997 (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
- Louis Harris and Associates, Inc. - Medicare Survey (96015) - Administration, 1995-1998 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Louis Harris and Associates, Inc. - Medicare Survey (96015) - Grant Products, 1995-1996 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- George Washington University - Soafer (970956) - Providing Medicare Beneficiaries with Report Cards to Compare HMO Quality in New York City - Proposal Development, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- George Washington University - Soafer (970956) - Providing Medicare Beneficiaries with Report Cards to Compare HMO Quality in New York City - Administration and Background, 1996-1999 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- George Washington University - Soafer (970956) - Providing Medicare Beneficiaries with Report Cards to Compare HMO Quality in New York City - Grant Products, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- University of California, San Francisco (971038 PDF) - Understanding the Evolution of Medicare Policy, 1998-2000 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Advancing the Well-Being of Elderly People Advisory Committee Meeting, 1999 February (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Advancing the Well-Being of Elderly People Advisory Committee Meeting, 1999 July 29 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Advancing the Well-Being of Elderly People Advisory Committee Meeting, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Harvard Medical School - Newhouse (96952) - Paying Medicare Managed Care Plans, 1996-1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Yale University - Inouye (94-90, 95-47) - Grant Products, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Alliance for Aging Research (AAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (95-17) - Proposal and Background, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Alliance for Aging Research (AAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (95-17) - Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Alliance for Aging Research (AAR) - The Paul Beeson Faculty Scholars in Aging Research (95-17) - Grant Products, 1995-1997 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- The Urban Institute - Frail Elders Project (95-46) - Administration, 1995-1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- The Urban Institute - Frail Elders Project (95-46) - Grant Products, 1995-1996 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- University of Minnesota - Kane (95-48) - Evaluation of Long Term Care - Proposal, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- University of Minnesota - Kane (95-48) - Evaluation of Long Term Care - Administration, 1995-1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- University of Minnesota - Kane (95-48) - Evaluation of Long Term Care - Grant Products, 1995-1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc. (NBER) - Garber (96170) - Medicare at the End of Life: Diseases, Treatment Patterns and Costs - Grant Products, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Dartmouth College - Wasson (96909) - Four State Initiative to Monitor and Assess Long-Term Care Needs, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Institute of Medicine (IOM) - End of Life (96908) (Box 20, Folder 2)
- National Academy for State Health Policy (NASHP) - Riley (96640) - Managed Care Iniatives for Low Income Elderly People - Grant Products, 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- National Academy of Aging - Friedland (96609), 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- National Academy of Aging - Friedland (96609) - Grant Products, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- National Academy of Aging - Friedland (96609) - Grant Products, 1998-1999 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- O'Brien (20020692) - Providing Better End of Life Care Within an Ethical Framework, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
- O'Brein - NJ Seed Project: Ethics, Education and Support for Nursing Homes, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Yale University - Inouye (990912) - Administration and Budget (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Yale University - Inouye (990912) - Correspondence, 2002-2004 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Yale University - Inouye (990912) - Articles and Background, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Yale University - Inouye (990912) - Grant Products, 1999-2003 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Yale University - Inouye (990912) - Project Development, 1999-2000 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Brandeis University - Bishop (990136) - Proposal Development, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Brandeis University - Bishop (990136) - Administration and Correspondence, 1998-2004 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Brandeis University - Bishop (990136), 2002-2003 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
- Brandeis University - Bishop (990136) - Grant Products, 1999-2001 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
- Brandeis University - Gittell (20020185) - Background (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Brandeis University - Gittell (20020185) - Proposal Development, 2001-2002 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Brandeis University - Gittell (20020185) - Administration and Budget, 2001-2004 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- National Citizens Coalition for Nursing Home Reform - Proposal, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- U.S. Pharmacopeia - Eng (PDF 20010563), 2002 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Alliance for Aging Research - Perry (20020704), 2002-2004 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- UCLA - Schnelle (20010121), 2001-2003 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- UCLA - Schnelle (20010121) - Administration and Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- UCLA - Schnelle (20010121) - Proposal Development, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- UCLA - Schnelle (20010121) - Grant Products (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
- UCLA - Schnelle (20010121) - Grant Products (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
- University of Wisconsin - Zimmerman (990499) - Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- University of Wisconsin - Zimmerman (990499) - Administration and Background, 1999-2002 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- University of Wisconsin - Zimmerman (990499) - Proposal Development, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- University of Wisconsin - Zimmerman (990499) - Grant Products (Box 26, Folder 6)
- University of Wisconsin - Zimmerman (990499) - Grant Products (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
- National Citizens' Coalition for Nursing Home Reform - Burger, 1999-2001 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- National Citizens' Coalition for Nursing Home Reform - Burger, 2001-2002 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
- Alliance for Aging Research - Perry (20020704) - Grant Products, 2003-2004 (Box 28, Folder 3-4)